Guide to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Audio Collection ALBA.AUDIO.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Audio Collection
1964-2002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade
ALBA.AUDIO.001
2.3 Linear Feet in 1 flat box, 1 card box, and 6 boxes
175 audiocassettes
The Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade was formed in 1937 by American men and women who volunteered for the Abraham Lincoln Brigade in the Spanish Civil War as they began to return from Spain. The Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Audio Collection consists of 175 audio cassettes collected by or related to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB). The recordings date from 1964 to 2002 and include interviews with veterans, recordings of live events in Spain, musical recordings, and recordings of VALB events.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Most of the audio recordings in the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Audio Collection came to New York University in January 2001 as part of the original acquisition of ALBA collections, formerly housed at Brandeis University. The accession number associated with this acquisition is 2001.208. Additional interviews and other materials were added to the collection after 2001.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three series:
Series I: Interviews, Speeches, Discussions, 1964-2002
Series II: Public events, 1970-1999; and
Series III: Music, 1976-2002.
Each recording has been assigned a unique item number (e.g. ALBA A 1-001), and the collection is arranged in item number order. For Series I, the item number order roughly follows the alphabetical order of the last name of the narrator, with a few exceptions. Some tapes contain multiple interviewees and are ordered according to how the names were written on the cassette. Recordings in Series II and III are arranged alphabetically by title.
Historical Note
The Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade was formed in 1937 by American men and women who volunteered for the Abraham Lincoln Brigade in the Spanish Civil War as they began to return from Spain. The Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) adopted a constitution and a formal structure in 1939. VALB originally raised money for the Spanish Republic, assisted wounded veterans, helped veterans resettle and find jobs, and attempted to alert the American public to the significance of the Spanish Civil War and the Loyalist cause. In later years, VALB campaigned against Francisco Franco's regime in Spain, assisted refugees, and addressed other political issues, including the United States's foreign policy in Cuba, Nicaragua, and Vietnam. In addition to their headquarters in New York City, VALB had posts in Los Angeles and San Francisco, California; Chicago, Illinois; and informal groups in other cities and regions.
Scope and Content Note
The Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Audio Collection consists of 175 audio cassettes collected by or related to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB). The recordings date from 1964 to 2002 and include interviews with veterans, recordings of live events in Spain, musical recordings, and recordings of VALB events. The latter includes events such as the 50th anniversary celebrations in the Bay Area of California and in New York, New York. The interviews with veterans focus on their memories of their time in Spain.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to some audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Audiovisual materials that have not been preserved may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact [Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596] with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Personal narratives, American.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Songs and music.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Veterans.; Audiocassettes.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, American -- Interviews.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Biography; Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Abraham Lincoln Battalion; Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Brigada Internacional, XV
- Series I: Interviews, Speeches, Discussions, 1964-2002; 1.8 Linear Feet in 5 boxes and 1 card box
  Scope and Contents
  This series includes audio recordings of interviews with individual veterans and small groups, speeches and discussions in classes, and interviews aired on radio programs. Materials date from 1964 to 2002.
  - Alvarez del Vayo, Julio (Interview), undated; cuid15100 (Box Shared Tamiment 078, Cassette 1-001)
  - Bailey, Bill (Interview), undated; cuid15101 (Box Shared Tamiment 078, Cassette 1-002)
  - Balchowsky, Edward R. (Interview in Spain by Blythe Allison Bennett), October 1986; cuid15102 (Box Shared Tamiment 078, Cassette 1-003)
  - Balchowsky, Edward R.; Milton Wolff; Louis (Lou) Gordon (Interview in Spain by Blythe Allison Bennett), October 1986; cuid15103 (Box Shared Tamiment 078, Cassette 1-004)
  - Beebe, Vernold (Interview), 1970-07-29; cuid15104 (Box Shared Tamiment 124, Box Shared Tamiment 078, Cassette 1-005)
  - Bessie, Alvah Cecil (Interview) [tape 2 of 4], undated; cuid15105 (Box Shared Tamiment 078, Cassette 1-006)
  - Bessie, Alvah Cecil (Interview) [tape 3 of 4], undated; cuid15106 (Box Shared Tamiment 078, Cassette 1-007)
  - Bessie, Alvah Cecil (Interview) [tape 4 of 4], undated; cuid15107 (Box Shared Tamiment 078, Cassette 1-008)
  - Birnbaum, Saul; Harry Fisher; Robert Gladnick (Interview), undated; cuid15108 (Box Shared Tamiment 078, Cassette 1-009)
  - Birnbaum, Saul; Harry Fisher; Robert Gladnick (Interview), undated; cuid15109 (Box Shared Tamiment 078, Cassette 1-010)
  - Boudin, Leonard (at the University of Colorado speaking on the U. S., Nicaragua and the World Court) [Master], 1986-03-19; cuid15110 (Box Shared Tamiment 078, Cassette 1-011)
  - Boudin, Leonard (at the University of Colorado speaking on the U. S., Nicaragua and the World Court) [Copy], 1986-03-19; cuid15111 (Box Shared Tamiment 078, Cassette 1-012)
  - Brier, Morris (BROKEN) [tape 1 of 2], 1981-09-02; cuid15112 (Box Shared Tamiment 078, Cassette 1-013)
  - Brier, Morris (Interview) [tape 2 of 2], 1981-09-02; cuid15113 (Box Shared Tamiment 078, Cassette 1-014)
  - Brown, Archie (Interview), 1988-05-10; cuid15114 (Box Shared Tamiment 078, Cassette 1-015)
  - Cogswell, Theodore Rose; Arthur Harold Landis (Letter from Cogswell to Landis), undated; cuid15115 (Box Shared Tamiment 078, Cassette 1-016)
  - Collins, Joe; George Henry Leiviska (Interview), September 1968; cuid15116 (Box 2, Cassette 1-017)
  - Dent, Wally; Lionel Edwards; Fred Mattis Corter (Interview on Canadian Radio Program "As It Happens")[Master], 1981-02-16; cuid15117 (Box 2, Cassette 1-018)
  - Dent, Wally; Lionel Edwards; Fred Mattis Corter (Interview on Canadian Radio Program "As It Happens")[Copy], 1981-02-16; cuid15118 (Box 2, Cassette 1-019)
  - Fisher, Harry (Interview on WNYC), undated; cuid15119 (Box 2, Cassette 1-020)
  - Fishman, Moe (Mosess); Harry Fisher; William Cane Van Felix (Interview on CWA Local 80 Radio Program, ? "Communique"), 1987-08-04; cuid15120 (Box 2, Cassette 1-021)
  - Friedman, Maurice Wolf (Interview with sister Muriel Eldrige, and husband Richard Eldrige), 1988; cuid15121 (Box 2, Cassette 1-022)
  - Gandall, William (Question and Answer), 1988-05-10; cuid15122 (Box 2, Cassette 1-023)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Duration: 92 minutes
  - Garlin, Sender (Interview on KGNU Radio, Boulder, CO), 1985-02-25; cuid15123 (Box 2, Cassette 1-024)
  - Garlin, Sender (Party in His Honor), 1986-03-01; cuid15124 (Box 2, Cassette 1-025)
  - Garlin, Sender (Public Speaking, University of Colorado)[tape 2], 1986-12-01; cuid15125 (Box 2, Cassette 1-026)
  - Garlin, Sender (Questions and Answers at University of Colorado), 1989-10-03; cuid15126 (Box 2, Cassette 1-027)
  - Gates, John (Interview) [tape 1 of 4], undated; cuid15127 (Box 2, Cassette 1-028)
  - Gates, John (Interview) [tape 2 of 4], undated; cuid15128 (Box 2, Cassette 1-029)
  - Gates, John (Interview) [tape 3 of 4], 1970-05-14; cuid15129 (Box 2, Cassette 1-030)
  - Gates, John (Interview) [tape 4 of 4], 1970-05-14; cuid15130 (Box 2, Cassette 1-031)
  - Gates, John (Memorial Meeting), 1992-06-19; cuid15131 (Box 2, Cassette 1-032)
  - Gates, John (Memorial), 1992-09-10; cuid15132 (Box 2, Cassette 1-033)
  - Gibbs, Theodore (Interview with Daughter, Michelle Gibbs re: Her Father), 1977; cuid15133 (Box 2, Cassette 1-034)
  - Giler, Henry (Public Speaking), 1974-01-04; cuid15134 (Box 2, Cassette 1-035)
  - Gladnick, Robert (Interview), undated; cuid15135 (Box 2, Cassette 1-036)
  - Gladnick, Robert (Interview), undated; cuid15136 (Box 2, Cassette 1-037)
  - Gladnick, Robert (Interview), undated; cuid15137 (Box 2, Cassette 1-038)
  - Gladnick, Robert (Interview), undated; cuid15138 (Box 2, Cassette 1-039)
  - Gladnick, Robert (Interview), undated; cuid15139 (Box 2, Cassette 1-040)
  - Gladnick, Robert (BROKEN), undated; cuid15140 (Box 2, Cassette 1-041)
  - Gladnick, Robert (BROKEN), undated; cuid15141 (Box 2, Cassette 1-042)
  - Gladnick, Robert (Interview), undated; cuid15142 (Box 2, Cassette 1-043)
  - Gladnick, Robert (Interview), undated; cuid15143 (Box 2, Cassette 1-044)
  - Gladnick, Robert (Interview), undated; cuid15144 (Box 2, Cassette 1-045)
  - Gladnick, Robert (Interview), 1970-05-19; cuid15145 (Box 2, Cassette 1-046)
  - Goldring, Benjamin (Asking Question of Roy Cohn; audio recording of a TV show), 1980-07-20; cuid15146 (Box 2, Cassette 1-047)
  - Hakam, Harry; Milton Wolff (Interview in Spain by Blythe Allison Bennett), October 1986; cuid15147 (Box 2, Cassette 1-048)
  - Harriman, Emanuel (Manny); Donald Blair Macleod; Sidney Levine; George Foucek; Arthur Harold Landis (Interview), 1964-10-18; cuid15148 (Box 2, Cassette 1-049)
  - Hollander, Herman (Interview), 1970-06-15; cuid15149 (Box 2, Cassette 1-050)
  - Hollander, Herman (BROKEN), 1970-06-15; cuid15150 (Box 2, Cassette 1-051)
  - Hollander, Herman (Interview), 1980-01-10; cuid15151 (Box 2, Cassette 1-052)
  - Hollander, Herman (Interview), 1980-01-10; cuid15152 (Box 3, Cassette 1-053)
  - Iceland, Benjamin Isaac (Interview), undated; cuid15153 (Box 3, Cassette 1-054)
  - Jones, James Moore (Interview), undated; cuid15154 (Box 3, Cassette 1-055)
  - Kailin, Clarence; Edie Newman; Milton Felson (Interview on WORT-FM) [Master], 1996-12-19; cuid15155 (Box 3, Cassette 1-056)
  - Kailin, Clarence; Edie Newman; Milton Felson (Interview) [Copy], 1996-12-19; cuid15156 (Box 3, Cassette 1-057)
  - Kobeluch, John (Interview), undated; cuid15157 (Box 3, Cassette 1-058)
  - Landis, Arthur Harold (Discussing his Cancer and Interviewing his Doctor for Article), undated; cuid15158 (Box 3, Cassette 1-059)
  - Landis, Arthur Harold (Interview), undated; cuid15159 (Box 3, Cassette 1-060)
  - Landis, Arthur Harold (Interview), undated; cuid15160 (Box 3, Cassette 1-061)
  - Landis, Arthur Harold (Interview), undated; cuid15161 (Box 3, Cassette 1-062)
  - Landis, Arthur Harold (Notes for future writing), undated; cuid15162 (Box 3, Cassette 1-063)
  - Landis, Arthur Harold (Outlining a Story), undated; cuid15163 (Box 3, Cassette 1-064)
  - Landis, Arthur Harold; Donald Blair MacLeod (Interview), undated; cuid15164 (Box 3, Cassette 1-065)
  - Landis, Arthur Harold; Donald Blair MacLeod (Letter from Landis to Macleod), undated; cuid15165 (Box 3, Cassette 1-066)
  - Landis, Arthur Harold; Evelyn Hutchins; Carl Frederick Geiser (Interview), undated; cuid15166 (Box 3, Cassette 1-067)
  - Landis, Arthur Harold; Steve Nelson (Interview), 1978; cuid15167 (Box 3, Cassette 1-068)
  - Lanser, Manny (Morris) (Interview) [tape 1 of 2], 1997-03-08; cuid15168 (Box 3, Cassette 1-069)
  - Lanser, Manny (Morris) (Interview) [tape 2 of 2], undated; cuid15169 (Box 3, Cassette 1-070)
  - Levenson, Leonard Bertram; Samuel Gonshak; Charles Nusser (Interview in Spain by Blythe Allison Bennett), October 1986; cuid15170 (Box 3, Cassette 1-071)
  - Levine, Sidney (Interview and songs recorded from a record), 1977-09-21; cuid15171 (Box 3, Cassette 1-072)
  - Levine, Sidney (Interview), undated; cuid15172 (Box Shared Tamiment 124, Box 3, Cassette 1-073)
  - Levine, Sidney (Interview), 1977-09-23; cuid15173 (Box Shared Tamiment 124, Box 3, Cassette 1-074)
  - Levine, Sidney (Recorded at a Birthday Party), 1977-04-29; cuid15174 (Box 3, Cassette 1-075)
  - Mattersdorfer, Fred; Wally Dent; Lionel Edwards (Interview on "As It Happens" with Alan Maitland, Toronto, Canada), 1981-02-16; cuid15175 (Box 3, Cassette 1-076)
  - Matthews, William (aka Matvenko) (Interview) [tape 1 of 2], 1980-06-21; cuid15176 (Box 3, Cassette 1-077)
  - Matthews, William (aka Matvenko) (Interview) [tape 2 of 2], 1980-06-21; cuid15177 (Box 3, Cassette 1-078)
  - Nelson, Steve (Interview) [tape 1 of 3], undated; cuid15178 (Box 3, Cassette 1-079)
  - Nelson, Steve (Interview) [tape 2 of 3], 1970-02-21; cuid15179 (Box 3, Cassette 1-080)
  - Nelson, Steve (Interview) [tape 3 of 3], undated; cuid15180 (Box 3, Cassette 1-081)
  - Nelson, Steve (Interview), undated; cuid15181 (Box 3, Cassette 1-082)
  - Nelson, Steve (Interview), 1978; cuid15182 (Box 3, Cassette 1-083)
  - Nusser, Charles (Interview with Judith Montell on WGBH, Boston), 1992-11-12; cuid15183 (Box 3, Cassette 1-084)
  - Nusser, Charles (Interview), 1970-07-18; cuid15184 (Box 3, Cassette 1-085)
  - Nusser, Charles (Interview), 1970-06-18; cuid15185 (Box 3, Cassette 1-086)
  - Nusser, Charles (Interview), 1991-11-12; cuid15186 (Box 3, Cassette 1-087)
  - Nusser, Charles; Harry Fisher, Vaughn Love (Discussing Oliver Law on WNYC radio), 1989-02-08; cuid236 (Box 3, Cassette 1-088, Box Shared Tamiment 124, Cd 1-088)
  - Nusser, Charles; Harry Fisher, Vaughn Love (Discussing Oliver Law on WNYC radio), 1989; cuid237 (Box 3, Cassette 1-089, Box Shared Tamiment 124, Cd 1-089)
  - Parker, Max (Narration of experiences in Spain and songs)[related to "Al Tocar Diana"], undated; cuid15187 (Box 4, Cassette 1-090)
  - Parker, Max; Milton Wolff; Manny (Morris) Lanser (Interview in Spain by Blythe Allison Bennett), October 1986; cuid15188 (Box 4, Cassette 1-091)
  - Peck, Samuel (Interview) [tape 1 of 2], 1980-01-19; cuid15189 (Box 4, Cassette 1-092)
  - Peck, Samuel (Interview) [tape 2 of 2], 1980-01-19; cuid15190 (Box 4, Cassette 1-093)
  - Randall, Jr., Harry Wayland (Interview with Erika Gottfried) [tape 1 of 2] [Master], 2002-04-10; cuid15191 (Box Shared Tamiment 124, Box 4, Cassette 1-094)
    Other Finding Aids
    A transcript of this interview is available and may be requested for research.
  - Randall, Jr., Harry Wayland (Interview with Erika Gottfried) [tape 2 of 2] [Master], 2002-04-10; cuid15192 (Box Shared Tamiment 124, Box 4, Cassette 1-095)
  - Randall, Jr., Harry Wayland (Interview with Erika Gottfried) [tape 1 of 2] [Copy], 2002-04-10; cuid15193 (Box 4, Cassette 1-096)
  - Randall, Jr., Harry Wayland (Interview with Erika Gottfried) [tape 2 of 2] [Copy], 2002-04-10; cuid15194 (Box 4, Cassette 1-097)
  - Randall, Jr., Harry Wayland (Interview with Erika Gottfried) [Master], 2002-09-12; cuid15195 (Box Shared Tamiment 124, Box 4, Cassette 1-098)
  - Randall, Jr., Harry Wayland (Interview with Erika Gottfried) [Copy], 2002-09-12; cuid15196 (Box 4, Cassette 1-099)
  - Rody, John (Interview) [tape 1 of 3], 1980-07-07; cuid15197 (Box 4, Cassette 1-100)
  - Rody, John (Interview) [tape 2 of 3], 1980-07-07; cuid15198 (Box 4, Cassette 1-101)
  - Rody, John (Interview) [tape 3 of 3], 1980-07-08; cuid15199 (Box 4, Cassette 1-102)
  - Sennett, William; Donald Blair MacLeod (Interview), August 1981; cuid15200 (Box 4, Cassette 1-103)
  - Stamm, Morris (Public Speaking on trip to Spain; Recorded by David M. Miller) [tape 1 of 2], 1977-11-11; cuid15201 (Box 4, Cassette 1-104)
  - Stamm, Morris (Public Speaking on trip to Spain; Recorded by David M. Miller) [tape 2 of 2], 1977-11-11; cuid15202 (Box 4, Cassette 1-105)
  - Steck, Robert (Interview by Byron T. Wells) [tape 1 of 7], undated; cuid15203 (Box 4, Cassette 1-106)
  - Steck, Robert (Interview by Byron T. Wells) [tape 2 of 7], undated; cuid15204 (Box 4, Cassette 1-107)
  - Steck, Robert (Interview by Byron T. Wells) [tape 3 of 7], undated; cuid15205 (Box 4, Cassette 1-108)
  - Steck, Robert (Interview by Byron T. Wells) [tape 4 of 7], 1999-07-25; cuid15206 (Box 4, Cassette 1-109)
  - Steck, Robert (Interview by Byron T. Wells) [tape 5 of 7], undated; cuid15207 (Box 4, Cassette 1-110)
  - Steck, Robert (Interview by Byron T. Wells) [tape 6 of 7], undated; cuid15208 (Box 4, Cassette 1-111)
  - Steck, Robert (Interview by Byron T. Wells) [tape 7 of 7], undated; cuid15209 (Box 4, Cassette 1-112)
  - Taylor, Robert Munson (Interview) [tape 1 of 2], 1980-06-27; cuid15210 (Box 4, Cassette 1-113)
  - Taylor, Robert Munson (Interview) [tape 2 of 2], 1980-06-27; cuid15211 (Box 4, Cassette 1-114)
  - Toney, Anthony; Al Warren; Ralph Fasanella (Interview), 1986-10-27; cuid15212 (Box 4, Cassette 1-115)
  - Unidentified (Interview on lessons to be learned from SCW), 1982; cuid15213 (Box 4, Cassette 1-116)
  - Unidentified Veterans (Interview and speaking amongst themselves at a meeting), 1970-12-06; cuid15214 (Box 4, Cassette 1-117)
  - Unidentified Veterans (Interview and speaking amongst themselves at a meeting), undated; cuid15215 (Box 4, Cassette 1-118)
  - Unidentified Veterans (Interview for British Documentary), undated; cuid15216 (Box 4, Cassette 1-119)
  - Unidentified Veterans (Interview) [tape 1 of 2], undated; cuid15217 (Box 4, Cassette 1-120)
  - Unidentified Veterans (Interview) [tape 2 of 2], undated; cuid15218 (Box 4, Cassette 1-121)
  - Unidentified Veterans (Interview), undated; cuid15219 (Box 4, Cassette 1-122)
  - Unidentified Veterans (Interview), undated; cuid15220 (Box 4, Cassette 1-123)
  - Unidentified Veterans (Interview), undated; cuid15221 (Box 4, Cassette 1-124)
  - Veltford, Jr., Theodore Ernest (Interview), 1988-05-04; cuid15222 (Box 4, Cassette 1-125)
  - Voros, Sandor (Interview) [tape 1 of 4], 1970-05-20; cuid15223 (Box 4, Cassette 1-126)
  - Voros, Sandor (Interview) [tape 2 of 4], 1970-05-20; cuid15224 (Box 4, Cassette 1-127)
  - Voros, Sandor (Interview) [tape 3 of 4], 1970-05-20; cuid15225 (Box 4, Cassette 1-128)
  - Voros, Sandor (Interview) [tape 4 of 4], 1970-05-20; cuid15226 (Box 4, Cassette 1-129)
  - Watson, William (Professor at MIT discussing previously unpublished Hemingway piece on SCW on "All Things Considered," National Public Radio), 1982-12-02; cuid15227 (Box 4, Cassette 1-130)
  - Weissman, Irving (BROKEN), undated; cuid15228 (Box 5, Cassette 1-131)
  - Weissman, Irving (Memorial), 1999-02-20; cuid15229 (Box 5, Cassette 1-132)
  - Wolff, Milton (Interview with David Marsamian on KGNU radio), 1985-02-27; cuid15230 (Box 5, Cassette 1-133)
  - Wolff, Milton (Interview with Gonzalo Santo on KGNU radio), 1985-02-26; cuid15231 (Box 5, Cassette 1-134)
  - Wolff, Milton (Interview), 1970-05-22; cuid15232 (Box 5, Cassette 1-135)
  - Wolff, Milton (Interview), undated; cuid15233 (Box 5, Cassette 1-136)
  - Wolff, Milton; Carl Frederick Geiser; Pete Randall B. Smith (Interview), 1980; cuid15234 (Box 5, Cassette 1-137)
- Series II: Public Events, 1970-1999
  This series contains audio recordings of presentations by veterans on trips to Nicaragua and China, recordings from the veterans' trip to Spain in 1986, and the 50th anniversary celebrations in the Bay Area of California and New York, New York. Materials date from 1970 to 1999.
  - España en Ilamas, undated (Box 5, Cassette 1-140)
  - Poetry by Unidentified Veteran; Mayor of Candeza Speech [Spanish with translator], 1983-08-02 (Box 5, Cassette 1-141)
  - Spanish Civil War 50th Anniversary Reception in Madrid, October, 1986
    - Part one, cuid45058 (Box 5, Cassette 1-142)
      Duration: 78 minutes
      This recording includes a musical performance, as well as speeches by Antonio Beltrán, President of the Democratic Fraternity of the Military of the Republic of Spain; Francisco Domínguez, President of the League of the Mutilated and the Disabled by War; a member of the Polish delegation in representation of the International Brigade; and Juan Barranco Gallardo, Mayor of Madrid.
    - Part two, cuid45060 (Box 5, Cassette 1-147)
      Duration: 64 minutes
      This recording includes musical performances, as well as speeches by Antonio Beltrán, Juan Barranco Gallardo, Victoria Vega, and an unidentified speaker. Topics discussed include global peace and the recognition of "Los Voluntarios de la Libertad" (Freedom Volunteers) from World War II. Audio recorded by Blythe Allison Bennett.
    - Part three, cuid45061 (Box 5, Cassette 1-148)
      This recording includes musical performances, a film screening, and speeches by Antonio Beltrán and Juan Barranco Gallard. Audio recorded by Blythe Allison Bennett.
  - Speech on Spain, undated; cuid45059 (Box 5, Cassette 1-143)
    Duration: 47 minutes; Preservation Note: Poor audio.
    An unidentified speaker discusses the Spanish Transition to Democracy, the Spanish military, the role of Spain in NATO, and U.S. Relations with Spain.
  - Trip to China: Veterans, undated (Box 5, Cassette 1-144)
  - Trip to Nicaragua (Speech and Discussion) [Spanish and English], undated (Box 5, Cassette 1-145)
  - Trip to Spain: Meeting [Spanish and English], undated (Box 5, Cassette 1-146)
  - VALB 46th Anniversary Dinner, (NY Post Tom Wicker and Sister Benedicta), 1983-04-20 (Box 5, Cassette 1-149)
  - VALB 50th Anniversary Celebration
    - "Broken", August 7, 1986 (Box 5, Cassette 1-138)
    - Charles Nusser reading / speaking, circa 1986 (Box 5, Cassette 1-139)
    - Bay Area Post, Music and Dramatic Reading, circa 1986 (Box 5, Cassette 1-150)
    - Bay Area Post, Music and Dramatic Reading -- Tape 1 of 2, April 27, 1986 (Box 5, Cassette 1-151)
    - Bay Area Post, Music and Dramatic Reading -- Tape 2 of 2, April 27, 1986 (Box 5, Cassette 1-152)
    - NY Post, Music and Dramatic Reading, WBAI Broadcast, April 7, 1986 (Box 5, Cassette 1-153)
    - NY Post, Music and Dramatic Reading -- Master 1 of 2, April 7, 1986 (Box 5, Cassette 1-154)
    - NY Post, Music and Dramatic Reading -- Master 2 of 2, April 7, 1986 (Box 5, Cassette 1-155)
    - NY Post, Music and Dramatic Reading -- Copy 1 of 2, April 7, 1986 (Box 5, Cassette 1-156)
    - NY Post, Music and Dramatic Reading -- Copy 2 of 2, April 7, 1986 (Box 5, Cassette 1-157)
    - NY Post, Music and Dramatic Reading -- Copy 1 of 2, April 7, 1986 (Box 5, Cassette 1-158)
    - NY Post, Music and Dramatic Reading -- Copy 2 of 2, April 7, 1986 (Box 5, Cassette 1-159)
  - VALB 55th Anniversary Dinner, April 26, 1992
    - NY Post -- Master (Box 5, Cassette 1-160)
    - NY Post -- Copy, 1992-04-26 (Box 5, Cassette 1-161)
- Series III: Music, 1976-2002